Gianluca Tranchedone

Senior Software Engineer specialised in developing applications for Apple devices and full stack Ruby on Rails development.

I'm founder of Cocoa Beans GT Ltd the company I use for my contract work, as well as for all my published projects for sale. Please ask me about those projects or visit http://cocoabeans.io to find out more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

September 2014 - Present

Shopa Ltd, London - UK

Contract Senior Software Engineer / Lead Mobile Developer

Shopa is one of the first Social Marketplaces, connecting retailers with customers through the power of social recommendation. At Shopa I've...

- Helped management come up with a focused long term vision for both mobile app and website
- Helped define the back-end system architecture and helped building a server-side REST API in Rails
- Built a couple of mobile app prototypes based on business goals using Objective-C and many frameworks in Cocoa Touch including Core Data, Core Animation, UIKit, Foundation and Social.
- Built the <u>Shopa for iPhone</u> app using TDD / BDD and other Extreme Programming techniques

October 2013 - September 2014

Lowdownapp Ltd, London - UK

Contract Senior Software Engineer / Lead Mobile Developer

Lowdownapp is a small startup focusing on making busy professional's life easier. In fact, their main app, Lowdown, is the fastest way to get meeting information. At Lowdownapp I've...

 Advised the founders on technologies and helped them planning their mobile strategy based on the vision they have for their product

- Developed the apps <u>Lowdown</u> and <u>HERE</u> and a range of contained private libraries that can be easily integrated in all projects via CocoaPods that were used in the development of the two apps. The apps where both developer using Objective-C and many frameworks in Cocoa Touch including Core Data, Core Animation, UIKit, Foundation and Social.
- Helped the CTO and backend developer defining the product and API

August 2013 - October 2013

Reply Ltd, London - UK

Contract Senior iOS Software Engineer

Reply is a leading Consulting, Systems Integration and Digital Services company. At Reply I've...

- Helped their in-house team meet a deadline with their customer (large European retailer) by quickly building a large portion of the mobile app they had to deliver
- Developed the iPad application, with particular focus on architecture and UI using Objective-C and many frameworks in Cocoa Touch including Core Data, Core Animation, UIKit, Foundation and Social
- Tutored their in-house team on technologies and methodologies to adopt, such as Core Data (data modelling and data persistence framework for iOS and Mac), Software Design Patterns and Automated Testing (TDD)

April 2013 - August 2013

Tictrac Ltd, London - UK

Contract Senior iOS Software Engineer

Tictrac is a small startup that aims at letting you discover more about yourself, by showing you all of your activities in one place. At Tictrac I've...

- Developed an Objective-C iOS SDK for third-parties interested in integrating the data an machine learning capabilities of the service into their own apps.
- Developed a prototype for the company's second-generation iOS app, related to the B2C offering of the company.

doo GmbH, Bonn - Germany

Senior iOS / OS X Developer

doo is a small startup that aimed at letting you get all your life's documents organised into one place by syncing with all cloud services you use and categorising them. doo is no longer supporting this business but focusing instead on the app Scanbot, only recently developed. At doo I've...

- Helped the in-house team develop their Mac app, later featured by Apple as "App of the Week" on the Mac App Store, using Objective-C and many frameworks in Cocoa including Core Data, Core Animation, AppKit, Foundation and Social.
- Started working on their iOS app, later featured by "Apple as App of the Week" on the App Store, using Objective-C and many frameworks in Cocoa Touch including Core Data, Core Animation, UIKit, Foundation and Social.

June 2011 - October 2012

Service2Media Ltd, Enschede - The Netherlands iOS Developer

Service2Media is an international Consulting and Digital Services company. At Service2Media I've worked with TV Channels Broadcasting and Banking clients of the company. More details about the experience at Service2Media can be provided upon request.

December 2009 - June 2011

Naples / Rome - Italy

Freelance / Independent iOS Developer

Experience during this period experience can be provided upon request.

Skills

- Test-Driven Development / Behaviour-Driven Development, Continuous Integration, Extreme Programming, Agile Software Development, Scrum, Kanban
- Objective-C, Swift, Ruby, Java, C / C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Xcode, AppCode, IntelliJ, RubyMine, Eclipse

 UIKit, AppKit, Foundation, Core Foundation, Core Animation, Core Graphics, Core Data, Social Framework... and most other frameworks included in the iOS and OS X SDKs

EDUCATION

September 2010 - June 2011

University of Naples "Federico II", Naples - Italy

BA in Computer Science

Dropped out to seek the work opportunity at Service2Media in the Netherlands.

September 2007 - March 2011

University of Naples "L'Orientale", Naples - Italy

BA in Comparative Literatures and Cultures (Japanese and American Studies)

Final Grade: 104/110 (First-Second grade equivalent)